CONTACT

9 M

Montreal

(1)

514 914-1663

lucie.plantier@protonmail.com

(7)

github.com/lucie-pl

(b)

linkedin.com/in/lucie-plantier/

0

lucie-pl.github.io/

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:

Ruby, Javascript, C#

Front-end:

HTML, CSS, Figma, Bootstrap, Stimulus, React

Back-end:

Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, .NET

Cloud service:

Heroku

Versioning tools:

Git, Github

Softwares and platforms:

Photoshop, Indesign, Mailchimp, Wix, Trello, Miro

LANGUAGES

French | English

LUCIE PLANTIER

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Enthusiastic, dynamic and team player, I have eight years' experience in **marketing**, **communications** and **event organization** in the film industry.

Recently pivoted into coding through Le Wagon's **Web Development bootcamp**.

Known for my **collaborative approach**, I bring a **strategic vision** and a blend of **technical and creative skills** to contribute effectively to web development projects.

PROJECTS

Notes Manager

- Web app to take and save notes
- Stack: React, Redux

Motion-Series

- TV show adviser web app
- Stack: React

Cuisinator - currently in progress

- Web app for me and my friends to gather and share cooking recipes, create our own categories and avoid ads or videos
- Stack: Ruby on Rails. React, PostgreSQL, Docker

MotionExp.

- Mobile web app prototype for moviegoers to build watchlist and history list, rate movies, get notified when specific movies are programmed in cinemas near you, and chat with friends
- Designed and developed in two weeks, I was team lead in a team of 3.
- Stack: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Bootstrap, Stimulus, Figma and Heroku
- Further developments planned: adapt it to work with an API, improve the friends features

E-Car

- Web application prototype that allows users to both rent electric cars based on their location, and offer their own vehicles for rent. E-Car is an Airbnb clone (marketplace).
- Developed in one week, in a team of 3.
- Stack: Ruby on Rails, Cloudinary, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Bootstrap & Heroku

EDUCATION

Web Development, Le Wagon Montreal - Canada

10/2023 - 12/2023

- 9-weeks full-time intensive coding bootcamp
- Implemented and shipped to production a marketplace prototype, E-Car
- Designed and shipped to production a prototype of a mobile web app for moviegoers, MotionExp.

Master in Marketing and communications,

Kedge Business School Bordeaux - France

09/2013 - 06/2017

VOLUNTEERING & INTERESTS

Organisations: Project manager at Festival Européen du Court-Métrage de Bordeaux 2015 (1 000 attendees over 2 days of competition)

Sports: Running, tennis

Culture: Movies, series

Hackathon:

 Releaf organised by Beslogic, Canopeum and Carbone Québec

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Communication coordinator. Montreal - Canada

Cinémas Beaubien, du Parc, du Musée (02/2019 - 09/2023)

Working in close collaboration with top management, and leading a team of two, I was responsible for all external communications as well as the partnerships' development for the three cinemas.

- Designing communication plans for the overall activities of the cinemas, and reporting them to the general management
- Establishing partnerships with strategic cultural organizations and building strong commercial relationships with the business ecosystem
- Timely follow up on the KPI and revising strategy as and when required

Executive assistant. Paris - France

mk2 Cinémas and mk2 Store (07/2017 - 07/2018)

In one of the top 3 largest cinemas in Paris (1.5 million admissions/year, with up to 11,000 spectators/day), I was leading a team of 40+ operators. My mission was to ensure the smooth running of the cinema, delivering increased commercial performance and an optimal customer experience.

- Acting as an interface between management and operational team to ensure smooth implementation of new tools and processes
- Analyzing daily KPIs in terms of attendance and deploy relevant action plans
- Responsible for the full HR management cycle: recruitment, ressource scheduling, training and performance monitoring

Marketing & communication assistant, Paris - France

SND - Groupe M6 (01/2017 - 06/2017)

Elaboration and implementation from A to Z the promotional strategy for theatrical releases on the French market. Worked on the following films: La La Land, Lion, Les As de la jungle, Ôtez-moi d'un doute, Seven sisters, You were never really here

- Define, plan and execute the purchase of advertising spaces to ensure an effective promotional campaign (print, radio, web)
- Managing and following up on media and non-media partnerships (up to 10 partners per film release)
- Organizing and planning the logistics of major events: press day, previews, international talent, internal screenings at M6

Project manager assistant, Paris - France

mk2 Agency / mk2 + (09/2015 - 02/2016)

Within MK2 agency, part of the MK2 group, I was in charge of events, mostly B2B, within the network of MK2 theatres (both public and private).

- Building commercial proposals in line with client briefs (budget from 2.5k up to 200k€ per event)
- Ensuring the administrative follow-up of client files, the timely operational implementation of the events and the relations with the various service providers (technical, caterers, valet parking, hostesses/hosts, furniture)